So, Hermes's agents are great because it
kind of feels like you have Claude code
or Codex right in your pocket at all
times. But, if you've ever tried to set
one up before or you're intimidated to
because you're worried about like the
local setup or buying a VPS, then this
video is for you because I'm going to
show you how simple and easy this is
with a managed Hermes's agent that you
can get up and running by the end of
this video. So, let's not waste any time
and just get straight into this one.
Okay, so real quick, I just want to
cover what the difference is between a
managed agent and a VPS Hermes's agent.
So, if you don't care about this, then
just go ahead and skip past this part of
the video. So, at a glance, here are
some of the quick hitters. The managed
Hermes's starting off at about six bucks
a month while the VPS can start off a
little bit more than that. So, they're
kind of the same price, but the managed
is like slightly cheaper. There's also
no server to buy or maintain on this
side, whereas on the VPS you are buying
and maintaining a server. It's still a
relatively easy setup. It's still a
one-click install, but there is more
setup required. If you guys are
interested in this version, then I have
a video which I will tag right up here
where I did it on a VPS. The setup is a
lot more guided. It's a lot less
intimidating, even though this still is
pretty easy, but there definitely is
more to configure and kind of like more
to remember cuz on this side you don't
have any Docker, no SSH, no ENV files,
whereas this side you do, but it's still
kind of builds you the container and the
traffic. So, it's still not like you
have to be super technical. You have
full root access over here, full control
over a lot of the config and anything
else that you want on your server,
whereas that's pretty much handled over
here and you just have one managed agent
in a box essentially. You've got
Telegram pre-wired over here. You still
get CLI access, and on the other side
you have to set that up yourself. And
you still own things like updates and
backups and firewall rules and container
health, but you don't have any extra
cost really beyond the VPS, but you can
also scale up the VPS later. Because
really a VPS is not just for Hermes's.
It's basically a private server, which
you could scale up with more compute,
more RAM. You could put other things in
there. So, you can have a bunch of
Hermes's agents in one VPS. You can have
N8N in there. You can have a bunch of
other things inside of this box, whereas
with managed, you're basically just
spinning up a new app every single time.
You just get more flexibility with the
VPS, but if you're not looking to be
scaling up a server with tons of
different things on it, then just start
with a managed agent. It's easier and
it's simple and it really will suffice
for probably like 98% of you guys out
there. But now that we're ready to
actually get this set up, all you have
to do is go to Hostinger. Go to
hostinger.com, create an account, and
then when you're in sort of your HPanel
is what it's called, it will look like
this. So, on the left-hand side you can
see you can do things on Hostinger like
websites, domains, emails, building
sites. And in the past I've shown some
methods of, you know, setting up a VPS
and putting something on that like N8N
and Hermes Agent and Open Claw and other
things like that. But today I want to
show you guys a method that's so much
simpler and it's actually cheaper. All
you have to do is come on the left-hand
side and you'll see AI Agents. We can
see Open Claw, Hermes, and N8N. So,
obviously today we're going to click on
Hermes Agent. You can see that I have
two AI automation apps in here and these
are both Hermes Agents. If I wanted to
spin up Open Claw or N8N, I could do so
right here as well, but we're going to
click on Hermes Agent. We're going to
click up top and go to get new app. And
then all I have to do is click on get
started for the Hermes Agent. And we're
going to go ahead and choose the plan
that we want for this Hermes Agent. If
you want to include AI credits, you can,
but I would just turn that off. I don't
think you're going to use those. You
could also get 1,000 free web scraping
credits if you'd like and you can also
get Agentic Mail. So, you can basically
have an email address for your AI Agent.
You could do this through Hostinger or
you could also do this through something
like Agent Mail. And by the way, if you
use the link in the description, you can
actually get taken to this landing page
that will help you set up your Hermes
Agent automation managed app and you can
use coupon code Nate Herc to get 10% off
if you're on a yearly plan. So, that has
to be the 12-month or the 24-month, but
you can use code Nate Herc here. It's
the exact same product, it's just a
different way to get there. So, make
sure you use the link in the description
and use the coupon code Nate Herc. And
now this is going to take like a minute
to get set up and then we're basically
there already. Okay, so now we have to
basically choose the model. So, Hermes
Agent is essentially the harness that
wraps around some sort of AI model,
whether that be Clawd or GPT or Gemini
or whatever you want to use. So, you can
click through here and insert an API
key. But, what I think you should do is
use your ChatGPT subscription because
you're going to get way more inference.
It's going to be way cheaper. So, you
can actually just check the box right
there and hit continue and it makes it
super easy. And now all you have to do
is go to this link, sign into your
ChatGPT account, copy in this code, and
then now your Hermes agent will be
powered by your ChatGPT subscription.
So, there we go. It said that I signed
into Codex. I can close the page, and
then this is going to take like 10
seconds to register. There you go.
Connected successfully. And now the next
step is we need to connect this to
Telegram. So, go ahead and get Telegram
if you don't have it already, and then
we'll go ahead and get this set up.
Okay, so this is going to be so simple
as you can see. All we have to do first
is we have to go in here and search for
the BotFather, which basically helps us
actually set up different agents. You
can see that I've made some over here.
Now, what we have to do in here is do a
new bot command, which helps us
create a new bot. So, I'm just going to
go ahead and call this one managed
Hermes demo and hit enter. And now we
have to choose a username, and this is
what has to actually be completely
unique and it has to end in bot. So, I'm
just going to go ahead and see if we
need to do managed Hermes demo
bot and see if that works. Cool. So, now
my agent is basically registered here.
You will find it at this address. You
have this access token, which is what
you have to copy. And over here in
Hostinger, you're going to paste that
access token in and then hit continue.
And then your next step is to get your
Telegram user ID. So, you're going to
come back into Telegram. You're going to
search for user info bot. And once you
do a  start in here to the user
info bot, it'll show you your ID, which
will be right there. You'll click on
that to copy it, and then you'll paste
that over here in Telegram and then hit
continue. And now you guys can see we're
basically like done. We basically just
have to go to the bot. We have to
activate it and start chatting with it.
So, I'm going to go back up here to my
BotFather actually, and then I can click
right here on the name of the agent that
we built, and then it'll take us into
the chat window with this new agent. I
can hit start, and this is going to
pretty much start the activation
process.
Now, it's a little confusing. You can
see here if I type in hello, it's not
actually going to register anything. Um,
I actually I guess I cut off the screen,
but normally it will say typing up here,
but we don't see that coming because we
haven't yet finished the setup. So,
don't get confused. Don't feel like you
did anything wrong if you are starting
to freak out right here. As you can see,
even when I send another message,
nothing happens. So, we're going to come
over here to the left-hand side and hit
finish setup. And then we have to
actually choose the AI model to use. So,
that's what basically is going to happen
right here. It's going to apply these
settings and then we choose the AI model
within ChatGPT that we want to use. So,
this is where we do that. You can see
obviously it says that we can change
this at any time from the dashboard if
we want to. And because we used our
OpenAI subscription, our Codex
subscription, we're obviously only going
to right now be choosing from GPT
models. So, right now I'll just stick
with Soul. I'll hit continue and this
will actually say that we're all done.
And what we're going to do now is click
on open app, which is going to open up
this little like dashboard. It's a
Hostingar dashboard, but it's a Hermes
dashboard. So, we can control a lot of
stuff here. We can come in here and say
hello. And now you can see that we're
actually able to talk to our Hermes
because we've fully set up. We've
connected to ChatGPT 5.6 Soul and this
should come back right here. And now you
can see if I go back over here to
Telegram and I actually go ahead and say
hello, now it should be able to see
this. You can see up top it says typing,
which I actually cut out. Sorry about
that. But now it should be able to spawn
right here. It says, "Hello. How can I
help you?" And so now you can see that
we started two different threads. We
have one here in the dashboard. We have
one here in Telegram. And we can
actually see that. This one right here
says, "Hello and help offer." This one
shows that this is from Telegram. So, if
I say something else back here like, "I
am Nate." This doesn't get sent over to
Telegram, but if I come over here and
say, "I am Nate." This should sync over
once again to this side because it's a
Telegram chat. As you can see, it popped
over. It said, "I am Nate." And it said,
"Yes, you're Nate." So, now you can kind
of control what channel are you speaking
through? Here's Telegram as you can see.
And then here is basically just
communicating through the dashboard. And
then of course, all of this syncs to
your phone. So, right here you can see
that this is the exact thread that I'm
on. And if I actually pull up my
Telegram real quick again right here,
and I say
"Hey, now I'm on my phone." It should be
able to pop up right there, and you guys
can see that now I have my Hermes agent
in my pocket, but I also have it on my
computer here. So, anyways, what
actually is this dashboard? So, you can
see here that we can have tasks. So, we
can actually create scheduled jobs, and
we can manage them here. So, very
similar to routines that you might
create in something like Claude or
Grokbot or Codex. We also over here have
a Kanban. So, as we have the agent or a
bunch of different sub-agents doing
things, it can actually start to create
tasks on here, and we can see who it's
assigned to, and we can see where the
status of everything actually lives. So,
if you guys have ever done the Hermes
dashboard before, it's kind of like
this, but this is basically just hosted
on Hostinger. We can also start to add
in some skills here. So, there's a bunch
of skills that already come in here that
we can go ahead and turn on or off. We
have Claude Code, we have Codex, we have
computer use, we have creative skills,
we have email, GitHub, media, and of
course, you can go ahead and add your
own skills by basically just putting in
the name, giving it a category, and then
you can paste in the YAML front matter.
So, let's say for example, I wanted to
go to my Claude folder of all of my
skills, right? And maybe I want to use
this like Excalidraw diagram skill. I
would basically just open this up real
quick. This comes through like here. I
would copy this all, and then I could
just paste it right in there
as it shows there, and then I can just
call this whatever I need to, which
would be Excalidraw diagram skill, and
then go ahead and add that as a skill.
And you can see the metadata is
basically the YAML front matter, which
is the name and when to actually use the
skill. We also have the memory, so we
can start to have notes on things that
we add. We can have a user profile, we
can have an agent soul, and we can have
the project context. We have different
spaces, we have our own profiles. So, as
you can see, basically everything can be
managed right here inside of this little
dashboard, and then you can just take it
to go on your Telegram whenever you need
to. So, what does this look like on the
HPanel? So, what you do is you come over
here to your Hermes agents. You can see
all of the different apps that you have
up and running, and here's where you can
actually go in and manage them. So, for
example, if I went into this one that we
just created, and we wanted to add in
some API keys, what we would do is come
in here to environment, and we would
start to add them in here. So, let's say
we wanted our Hermes agent to be able to
use something like Tavily.
Can you go ahead and try to use Tavily
to help me do some research?
I want you to look up voice AI agents.
Now, obviously, it's not going to be
able to use Tavily because we haven't
yet given it any sort of credential, but
it's going to first do research to see
how that actually works because, of
course, Hermes can search the web on its
own. So, here's what it tells us. I
tried, but Tavily is not currently
available because there's no Tavily API
key. So, what you want to do is go to
your HPanel, go to the dashboard, and
add this environment variable, which is
your Tavily API key, and then add in the
key. So, I'm going to copy this. I'm
going to go over to our HPanel in our
environment variable section and add
one. I'm going to paste in what it told
me to call it, and then for the value,
we have to go grab that key. So, for
example, with Tavily, I'd go over here.
I would grab this API key. I would hit
copy, go back into my environment
variables, paste that in, and hit add.
And then we're going to have to apply
changes and make sure that that saves.
Now, as that saves, it basically has to
like reset the dashboard. So, if I come
back into here, and I go ahead and
refresh, it's not going to let us in
right away because it had to reset the
environment so that the key actually
applies. So, all you have to do to get
your password is go back into the Hermes
dashboard, you click on this button
dashboard, you copy your password, go
back into this page, paste that in, hit
okay, log in, and then you're basically
back exactly where you were, and your
chats are saved.
And now,
Hey, so I just added my Tavily API key
into the environment variables. Can you
go ahead and just try to run that search
again on Tavily and tell me the sources
that you pulled from? And so, as you can
see, I didn't give it context on like
what I wanted it to search for because,
even though we like reset it, it still
has all of this context. It still can
see this whole conversation window. I'll
verify that the key is visible, then
I'll run a Tavily search for current
voice AI agent landscape. Although,
right here it says the Tavily API key is
not visible. So, sometimes this happens.
Most of the time what I just did exactly
will work. But hey, if it says that it's
not visible, all you have to do is
restart it real quick. So, please
restart the Hermes agent from the H
panel and then try again. So, same
process. We'll go back into the
dashboard. We'll click on this restart
button right here in the dashboard and
hit restart. And then once again, it's
just going to make you log in again. So,
this is going to start up. You might as
well copy the password real quick. Now
it says that it's running. I'll click on
open app. That actually saved our login
that time, so we didn't have to log in.
Most of the time you will, so just be
ready for that. And now I'm just going
to come in here and say try again. And
now you can see I came back in here. I
asked it to try again and then it comes
back with research and has sources. And
if I go over to my Tavily, you can see
that we were at zero out of 1,000
credits and now that search used up five
just to prove that it was actually using
our Tavily account. But now you're
pretty much off to the races. You have
Hermes agent set up and that was super
quick and super easy. What I would
recommend doing now is I would go to my
free school community and grab this
skill called the grill me. So, you can
get this in my free school community.
Link's in the description. And
basically, this grill me skill just
helps agents interview you to get to
know more about you. Because the first
thing that I want to do with my Hermes
agents when I get them set up is make
sure they have all the context about me.
So, if you already have like an AI
operating system and you have that
backed up to GitHub, then just give your
Hermes agent that and say, "Hey, read
through this GitHub repo. This is our
file structure. This is my projects, my
business context and just get to know me
a little bit." But if you don't have any
of that or if you want to make it
better, then go ahead and add the grill
me skill. So, as you guys saw, we just
did this earlier. I would go to skills.
I would go ahead and add one. I've got
my grill me skill right here, which I
will copy and just paste all of that in
there and call this the grill-me and go
ahead and add that skill. And now I'll
just go back to the chat and say,
"Hey, so I want you to get to know more
about me and my business and my goals so
you can help me out as best as possible.
Use the grill me skill on me to help
figure out what I do." Okay, Okay, that
accidentally got dictated as grooming.
So, I need to annunciate better. I'm
going to change this to grill me and
send that edit and now it should be able
to find that. And if you guys have
already been using Cloud Code and stuff,
you can see that this is very similar.
The way that it like thinks and the way
that it shows you what it's doing,
that's what I love about working with
these systems, especially in Telegram,
too. It will show you sort of like that
chain of thought. So, here you can see
that it located the grill me skill and
it started a new project called
brainstorm. So, it's going to keep all
of the data that we're talking about
right now. It's going to save that to
its memory. So, every time you do a
grill me, it's going to get better and
smarter. Anyways, you guys are now set
up and off to the races. Please let me
know what else you guys want to see
about Hermes. I wanted to keep this one
quick and I wanted to keep it about a
setup. But, if you want to see some
deeper dives on different ways to set
them up and different ways to get the
most out of it, then please let me know
in the comments what you guys want to
see. But, that's going to do it for
today. So, if you guys enjoyed or you
learned something new, please give it a
like. It definitely helps me out a ton.
And as always, I appreciate you guys
making it to the end of the video and
I'll see you on the next one.
Thanks, everyone.